Outsmart or be overtaken
Delivery Run is a action, thriller film directed by Joey Palmroos.
A food delivery driver gets caught in a deadly chase in the icy Minnesota wilderness, pursued by a crazed snowplow driver
for unknown reasons, facing life-threatening situations and forced to outsmart his relentless pursuer alone.
Lee, played by Alexander Arnold.
Nathan, played by Liam James Collins.
Jasper, played by Arthur Sylense.
Rebecca, played by Nadine Higgin.
Mr. Plow, played by Jussi Lampi.
Mark, played by Joey Palmroos.
Kiki's Delivery Service is a 1989 Japanese animated fantasy film written, produced, and directed
by Hayao Miyazaki, based on Eiko Kadono's 1985 novel Kiki's Delivery Service.
Animated by Studio Ghibli, the film stars Minami Takayama,
Rei Sakuma, Kappei Yamaguchi, and Keiko Toda.
The story follows Kiki (Takayama), a young witch who moves to the port city of
Koriko with her cat Jiji (Sakuma) and starts a flying courier service.
In 1987, Group Fudosha asked Kadono's publishers for the rights to the novel
to be made into a film by either Miyazaki or Isao Takahata.
Production began near the release of My Neighbor Totoro (1988).
Miyazaki initially worked as producer, but took over directing from
Sunao Katabuchi as he became more involved in the project.
As the novel is based on a fictional northern European country, Miyazaki and his team
traveled to locations such as Visby, Sweden, to research its landscape.
Miyazaki altered the story, adding new scenes to emphasize
the theme of independence and growing up.
According to Miyazaki, the film portrays the gulf between
independence and reliance among teenage Japanese girls.
Kiki's Delivery Service was released in Japan on July 29, 1989, by Toei.
It was the first Studio Ghibli film to be successful on initial
release, grossing a total of ¥4.3 billion ($31 million).
It received critical acclaim and multiple awards.
An English dub was produced by Streamline Pictures for
Japan Airlines international flights in 1989.
The Walt Disney Studios produced an English dub in 1997, which became the first film
under a deal between Tokuma and Disney to be released in English.
It was released to home media in 1998.
The film explores themes of winter, minnesota, wilderness, slacker, salesman.
The tone is intense.